hunter-ed.com 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy | Hunter Ed.com™

**Hunter Ed** is committed to protecting the privacy of its users. Because **Hunter Ed** gathers information about the users who choose to take the online certification exams, we believe you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the use of the information we collect. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather and how we use it. Please review the following policy to understand how the information you provide **Hunter Ed** will be treated.

## Information We Collect

In order to access the course material, users must register by providing personal information, such as name, date of birth, gender, city and state, e-mail address, and additional information that varies by state. This information is required by the state agencies responsible for hunting to issue your hunting safety certification card. When you are ready to take the exam, you will be required to pay by supplying a valid credit card number, expiration date, and name.

## What Hunter Ed Does With the Information We Collect

The personal information you supply to **Hunter Ed** will not be disclosed outside of **Hunter Ed** , except to securely transfer the personal data to the agency in your state responsible for Hunter Ed in order to issue your Hunter Ed safety education certificate. Your credit card information will be used only for processing your fee(s) related to taking the online certification exam. 

The online hunting safety courses on this site contain links to other sites. **Hunter Ed** is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites; however, we make our best effort to only provide links to reputable sites with acceptable content. Please remember that any information that is disclosed through these other sites may become public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

## With Whom Information Is Shared

We do not share, sell, or otherwise distribute information about individual users taking the online hunting safety exam with any third party, or any outside companies or organizations except the agency in your state that is responsible for hunting.

## Identity Theft and Security

All of your personal and credit card information is collected using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) Protocol, which encrypts your information and allows that information to be securely transferred to **Hunter Ed**. The SSL Certificate that protects the **Hunter Ed** site ensures that your identity is authenticated and that any and all information you enter on our website is private. After collection, your information is then stored on our servers at a location designed specifically to ensure that no unauthorized individuals have access to the server or its data.

## Children and Privacy

**Hunter Ed** encourages parents and guardians to spend time with their children online, and to be familiar with the sites their children visit. **Hunter Ed** values privacy and collects personal information from children in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA").

_**What Information Does Hunter Ed Collect From Children?**_

When children use or explore the **Hunter Ed** site, we may automatically collect certain technical information to improve and enhance our site. We may collect information regarding the user's operating system, the web browser, the user's online service provider, and the frequency with which the user visits various parts of our site. We may also collect persistent identifiers, such as cookies. Where we have actual knowledge that a child is using our site, this information will be used for the sole purpose of providing support for our internal operations to provide access to certain features of our site and to enable us to conduct research and analysis to improve performance of our site.

For users who elect to register for a course, **Hunter Ed** collects the user's name, date of birth, and e-mail address. For course payment, **Hunter Ed** may collect additional information, such as mailing address, billing address, and payment information.

Depending on the requirements of some state agencies, **Hunter Ed** may collect other information, such as weight, height, or other physical characteristics. Some states may also require collection of information, such as telephone number, gender, social security number, demographics, schooling, and vehicle license information.

If **Hunter Ed** obtains actual knowledge that a child under the age of 13 is using our site, we will only retain the child's name and e-mail address. We will then request that the child provide us with a name and e-mail address of his or her parent. In accordance with COPPA, **Hunter Ed** will then contact the parent to seek consent to retain and collect additional information from the child for purposes of fulfilling the course registration. **Hunter Ed** verifies the identity of a parent by requiring the parent to provide a credit card, debit card, or other online payment system so that **Hunter Ed** may make a nominal charge to confirm the parent's identity and consent to our collection of information from the child.

_**How Does Hunter Ed Use or Share Information Collected From Children?**_

**Hunter Ed** values and respects the privacy of personal information, including information collected from children. Children using our site may not make their personal information publicly available to others through our website.

**Hunter Ed** uses information collected from its users to provide them with requested services. For example, if a child provides information to us for purposes of registering for a safety course, we will use that information for purposes of providing the requested course. We will also disclose the information collected to the appropriate state agency so that the user, upon satisfactory completion of a course, can receive the appropriate state certification of completion. **Hunter Ed** does not otherwise share data with third parties, except where such third parties are contracted by **Hunter Ed** to support the internal operations of the company.

_**How Can Parents Access, Review, or Delete Information Collected From Their Child?**_

**Parental access:** Parents of students 18 years or younger may contact our Privacy Coordinator at the mailing address provided below if you would like to do any of the following:

  * Access and review personally identifiable information that **Hunter Ed** has collected online from your child,
  * Correct factual errors in such information,
  * Request to have this information deleted, or
  * Request that we no longer collect or maintain such information.

Please include your e-mail address and telephone number where we can reach you. **Hunter Ed** takes steps to verify the identity of anyone requesting information about a child and to ensure that the person is in fact the child's parent or legal guardian.

## How to Contact Hunter Ed

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the practices of this site, you can contact us at:

_**Hunter Ed**  
14086 Proton Rd.   
Dallas, TX 75244   
214-351-0461 _

**Hunter Ed** hopes this document answers your questions and concerns about our privacy policy. **Hunter Ed** is committed to protecting the privacy of our students.
  *[TX]: Texas
